So, Clawdbot / OpenClaw and Peter have single-handedly taken the open source community...
...forward into the future by six months or more in less than six weeks. Yep, there I said it.
I think despite the moltbook(.com) fiasco and the AI slop all over the place...
...I think Clawdbot is a net positive for the community.
Because everything seems to have happened in the open...
...and because there is so much transparency in the way everybody is approaching building and publishing.
And I'm glad to see that a lot of the community members, despite not necessarily being on the side of Clawdbot...
...have been kind and gracious enough to be a lovely safety net and exposed the vulnerabilities that have sort of surfaced.
I think it's good. As Mark Zuckerberg famously said, "Move fast and break things."
And I think in this case, the downside is negligible in comparison to what everybody's learned.
I maintain that there are more people now in the fold. Folks who had no idea about this...
...are now entering the circle, and those on the fringes have become much more active.
And the overall open source community has benefited significantly...
...thanks to all the PR and noise around Clawdbot and... Peter.
Of course, the one key thing that I want to highlight is it's also given a whole bunch of people...
...an amazing preview of what agentic AI truly can do.
So yeah, I really hope more people keep building. I hope they are not discouraged by some of the issues...
...and faux pas that have been exposed, but continue to learn from it and just keep shipping